[ Cheering ]
[欢呼]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Okay, thank you.
&gt;&gt; 好的 谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢
Good morning, everybody.
大家早上好
My name is Kasia.
我叫 Kasia
I'm here with my colleagues,
我和我的同事
Shuchen and James.
Shuchen 和 James 一起
And we are here to hand you the
为大家介绍在 App 中
keys to a better text input
呈现更好的输入法体验
experience in your app.
的关键
So, let's see what we're going
那么 让我们来看看
to talk about today.
我们今天要讲的内容
We're going to start with
我们将从如何
integrating the keyboard into
将键盘整合到布局中
your layout.
开始
And we're also going to talk
然后我们会谈到
about creating dynamic and more
怎样创造一个更加动态
interesting input accessory
更加有趣的输入辅助
views.
视图
We'll talk about making your app
我们还将讨论如何让你的 App
reach multilingual audiences,
接触到多语言的用户群体
using traits to make predictive
利用 Trait 让你的
quick type smarter in your app.
App 的 QuickType 更智能
Supporting hardware keyboards.
硬件键盘支持
Creating custom input views.
创建自定义输入界面
And finally, tips and best
最后 我们将给出关于
practices for keyboard
键盘扩展的一些建议
extensions.
和好的做法
So, I'm going to start with
下面我先开始谈谈
integrating the keyboard into
如何将键盘整合到
your app.
你的 App 的布局中
And for that, I'm going to show
为此 我要展示一个
you a screenshot of the app
我们专门为这个讨论
we've created for this talk.
所做的 App 的截图
It's called CatChat.
这个 App 叫 CatChat
It's for talking with your pets.
可以用它来跟你的宠物交流
Not just cats, but in my case,
不只是猫 但是对我来说
just cats.
只有猫
And we do have this available as
我们也提供这个 App 的代码
sample code so you can grab it
作为一个例子
from the site.
大家可以从我们的网站获取
Cat pictures not included.
但不包括猫的图片
So, let's get started with that.
好，那我们就从这里开始
You're going to see a lot of
你在后面的讨论中还会
this in the talk.
看到很多次这个App
And we're going to start with
我们就从
accounting for changing keyboard
应对键盘高度的变化开始
So, keyboards come in different
键盘有不同的尺寸
Depending on the language that
取决于用户
the user is using and the
正在使用的语言
settings that they've enabled,
和他们启用的设置
you might see different heights
你因此可能会在你使用的 App 中
of the keyboards that are used
看到不同高度的
in your app.
键盘
The English keyboard, with the
英语键盘
predictive bar, is one height,
因为有预测栏 是这样一个高度
whereas the Polish keyboard is
然而波兰语键盘
shorter, and the Chinese 10-key
就比较短，而中文的 10 键
pinyin keyboard, is taller than
拼音键盘 就比以上两者
both of those.
都要高一些
And there are third party
并且有一些第三方的
keyboards, which some of you may
键盘 很多可能你们也
have even written, and those do
写过 那些键盘就没有
not have a specific height
一个特定的高度要求
So, you're not ever guaranteed
所以你永远无法确保
to get a specific height for a
你的用户在你的 App 中使用
keyboard that a user is using in
一个特定的键盘高度
So, how do you account for this?
那么 你要怎样应对呢
Well, we have a set of
我们有一系列的
notifications.
通知功能
We tell you when the keyboard
我们会通知你键盘出现
shows, when it hides, and when
键盘隐藏和
the frame changes.
框架改变
And for each of these
在每一个通知中
notifications, we'll give you
我们会告诉你
the beginning and ending frame
你将获取的键盘的
that you get from the keyboard.
最开始与最终的框架
Now before we go into how to
在我们进入如何使用
work with that frame we're
我们给你们的框架之前
giving you, let's talk about a
我们不妨先来
bit of a special case, and
看一个特殊例子
that's the undocked keyboard.
就是脱离式键盘
In iPads, the user can actually
在 iPad 中 用户实际上可以
lift the keyboard off the bottom
从屏幕底部
of the screen, and move it
把键盘拉起来
around, as well as split it
并且来回移动
apart.
同时把键盘拆分
In that instance, you generally
在这种情况下 你一般
don't want your app to be trying
不会想要你的 App 总是尝试
to stay on top of the keyboard,
呆在键盘的上方
because they might move it all
因为用户可能会把键盘
the way to the top of the
挪到屏幕的最上方
screen, and then all your
那样你的全部
content is gone and that's no
内容都会消失
fun.
这可一点也不好玩
So, when the keyboard gets
因此 当键盘从屏幕底部脱离
undocked, we will send you a
我们会发送给你一个
"Hide" notification, just like
“隐藏”通知 就像我们之前
we would if the keyboard was
在键盘被关闭时
dismissed.
发送的一样
In most cases, that's how you're
大多数情况下 你们就要
going to handle it, as though
这样处理 就像
the keyboard was dismissed.
键盘被关闭时一样
If you do want to do something
如果你想做的很漂亮
clever, we will continue sending
我们会继续发送
you frame change notifications,
给你框架改变的通知
but for most people, what you're
不过对于大部分人而言
going to want to do is track the
你要做的是追踪
most recent hide or show event,
最近的一次隐藏或显示
and then deal with the keyboard
然后相应的处理键盘问题
accordingly before you deal with
之后再处理任何
any frame changes.
框架改变
So, the undocked keyboard is
所以 脱离式键盘是一种
something like this.
这样的东西
We have this nice scroll view.
我们看到这个滚动界面
And when the keyboard comes up,
然后当用户把键盘拉上去以后
the scroll view compensates.
这个滚动界面会补上下面的空白
When it's undocked, it takes up
当键盘脱离时 这个滚动界面
the full screen again.
会再次占满屏幕
And when the user docks it
当用户重新把键盘放回底部时
again, it comes back up so that
这个界面会恢复原状
you can see the entire
这样你就能看到整个
transcript of your delightful
你与你的猫的愉快
chat with your cat, which is
的聊天记录
important.
这可是件重要的事
So, that's the kind of special
这就大概是我要说
case.
的特殊例子
So, let's move on to actually
那么 我们继续讨论
working with that frame
如何使用我们给你的
notification that we give you.
框架通知
First things first.
首先
The keyboard is always full
键盘一直是
screen.
全屏的
It's always in the full screen
它一直是在全屏的
coordinate space.
坐标空间的
So, the first thing you do when
因此 你要做的第一件事
you get a keyboard frame from
当你从我们的通知中
one of our notifications, is
得到一个键盘框架时
convert it from the frame -- the
是把它从全屏坐标
screen coordinates, to your
转换到你的
local coordinates before you
本地坐标 然后你才能
start working with anything
开始处理其他
else.
事情
Because the keyboard can be full
由于键盘可以是全屏的
screen when you are not, and
而你的 App 可能不是
because you can you know --
因为你知道
there are all sorts of fun
在很多有趣的
situations where keyboards come
情况下 键盘会
up and down.
上上下下地乱跑
You always want to make sure to
你一定要确保
do this first.
先做这件事
You can't count on the frame
你不能依赖于
that you get being local to the
你所得到的框架恰好
frame of your app.
符合你的 App 的本地框架
Think about multitasking, for
举个例子 想想多线程工作
Then, if you do use the
然后 如果你确实使用
intersection of the frame that
我们给你的框架
we give you once you've
当你转换了它之后
converted it, and the view you
以及你的
want to use, you can then get
想用的界面 你就可以
the difference in height between
得到这两者之间的
the two of those -- or the
高度的区别 或者是
height of the keyboard as it
当键盘与你的界面重合时
will overlap your view, and use
它的高度 并且使用它
that to adjust for the keyboard.
来使你的界面适应键盘
So, let's talk about a couple
那么 我们来看几种
different kinds of layouts.
不同的界面布局
Let's start with layouts that do
我们从不会滚动的
not scroll.
界面开始
So, static layouts are generally
静止的界面一般是
a couple of text views, maybe a
一些文字视图 或者是
button, where the user doesn't
一个按钮 用户不用
have to move around a lot in
去移来移去就能
order to see everything in your
看到你的界面的
view.
全部内容
But you still want it to look
但你依然会希望它
nice with all keyboards.
在任何键盘的情况下都看起来整洁
In this instance, as an example,
这种情况下 举个例子
we have five text fields and
我们有五个文本框
they are tied together with UI
它们由 UI Layout Guides
Layout Guides acting as spacers.
绑定在一起作为空格存在
AT the top of the view, they're
在界面的顶部
using The Safe Area Edge Insets,
使用了安全区域边界插入
and at the bottom -- well, we'll
而在底部
talk about that in a second, but
我们等一下会谈到
the spacers change size
这些空格会
depending on what keyboard
因为不同键盘而改变大小
appears, so that it always shows
所以用户可以一直看到
all five of the text views to
全部的五个
the user.
文本框
So, how did we do that?
那么 我们是怎么做到的呢
Well, we created a custom UI
我们创建了一个自定义的
Layout Guide with a height
有高度限制的 UILayoutGuide
constraint that we hold onto so
保存下来
that we can adjust it later.
方便我们以后调整
The Layout Guide gets tied to
这个 Layout Guide 与
the bottom Safe Area Layout
你的页面底部的
Guide of your view.
安全区域 Layout Guide 绑定
And the top of the Layout Guide
然后当键盘出现的时候
should be tied to the bottom of
这个 Layout Guide 的顶部应该和
the view or spacer that you want
你希望出现在键盘上方
to appear directly on top of the
的空格或界面的底部
appeared.
绑定
Once you do that, you can do
当你完成了这些
your height conversion after
你就可以在
checking that the keyboard is
确定键盘可见之后完成高度转换
visible, and simply set that
简单地将
height constraint you held onto,
你所保存的高度限制
to the height of the keyboard.
设定到键盘高度上
If you pop that into a view
如果把它放入
animation block with N call
视图动画块 如果需要
layout if needed, you'll get the
可以加上一个调用界面
cool little animation between
你就能在刚才看到的
the keyboards that you saw, just
不同的键盘之间 获得一个酷炫的
a moment ago.
小动画
The more common case however,
然而 更常见的是
are scrolling layouts.
滚动界面
Layouts embedded in the scroll
你的布局嵌入在滚动
view so that the user can move
界面中 使得用户可以
between your views, and see
在不同界面中移动
everything that they need to
来看到他们想看
see.
的内容
In our case, we had this
在我们的这个例子中 在我们的
conversation View Controller in
Cat Chat App 里 我们用到了
our Cat Chat app.
这个会话视图控制器
And we want to make sure that
我们希望确保
you can scroll through the
你能够在任何时候都可以滚动查看
entire conversation at any time.
整个对话
So, we need to make sure that
所以 我们就要保证
the bottom of the table view is
调整表格视图底部
adjusted to how the entirety of
使你能够看到整个的
your chat transcript.
对话内容
So, how do you do this?
那么 要怎么做到呢
Very similar to before but a
与刚才方法非常相似
little less complicated.
但是不那么复杂
You simply make sure the
你只需要保证
keyboard's visible gain, do your
键盘可见 然后
frame conversion, get your
调整框架 得到你的合适的
height, and set the content
高度 之后把内容
inset of the scroll view.
正确地插入滚动界面就可以了
This is where that intersection
这就是交叉部分的
bit is helpful because if you
有用之处 因为如果你的
have a scroll view that does not
滚动界面不会
take up the full screen, you
占满整个屏幕
only want to offset it by the
你只需要补上
bit that's covered by the
键盘覆盖住的
keyboard.
那部分
Finally, you do need to handle
最后 在你调整了
scrolling the content, once
滚动插页之后
you've adjusted your scroll
你依然需要处理
insets.
内容的滚动
In the previous example, we were
在刚才的例子中 我们
actually using a UI Table View
实际上使用了一个 UITableViewController
Controller, which is even easier
它使整个过程更加容易
because it sets the insets for
因为它实际上帮你设置了插入内容
you, and all you have to do is
而你所要做的就是
scroll the content, which is
滚动内容 这样就
nice.
很方便了
In this case, we have a table
在这个例子中 我们有一个表格视图
view and we want the most recent
而我们希望最新的
item to show right above the
部分恰好出现在
keyboard.
键盘上方
So, we scroll the bottom cell,
因此 我们把最下面的单元
to the bottom of our inset table
滚动到我们插入的
view.
界面的底部
So, that is adjusting for the
这样就可以做出相应的调整
keyboard in your layout.
来适应界面中的键盘
Now, let's talk about extending
现在 我们要讨论一下如何
the keyboard with an input
用一个输入辅助视图
accessory view.
扩展键盘
The input accessory view, is a
输入辅助视图是一个
view right above the keyboard.
在键盘上方的视图
Here, it's a text view, and a
这个例子中 它是一个文本视图
button.
和一个按钮
IT can also be a tool bar with
它也可以是一个工具栏
some navigation buttons.
包括一些导航按钮
It can be a row of buttons.
它也可以是一排按钮
If can a couple of cool little,
它也可以是一些有趣的
you know, photos or something.
小照片什么的
Anything you want to put on
你可以把任何你想放的东西放上去
there, you can because it's just
因为它只是一个视图而已
How do you add this to the
那么如何把它加到
keyboard?
键盘上呢
Well, here we have the -- an
在我们的
input accessory view in our chat
对话视图控制器中
conversation view controller.
有一个输入辅助视图
And so, it's the host view
想要在键盘上
controller that wants to display
显示输入辅助
the keyboard with the input
视图的主视图
accessory view.
控制器
So, we make it part of the
然后 我们通过在
responder chain by returning
我们的对话视图控制器中
True for, "Can become first
让 canBecomeFirstResponder
responder," on our conversation
返回真 以使它成为响应链
view controller.
的一部分
Then, using either a custom view
然后 使用一个自定义视图
or a custom view controller,
或一个自定义视图控制器
depending on what exactly you
取决于你想对这个视图做
want to do with that view, you
什么操作
override the applicable method.
你覆盖掉相应的部分
Input accessory view, if you're
如果你使用视图
using a view.
就覆盖 inputAccessoryView
Input accessory view controller,
如果你使用视图控制器
if you're using a view
就覆盖
controller.
inputAccessoryViewController
So, the input accessory view
这样你所添加的输入辅助视图
that you add, is accounted for
会被列入
in frame change notifications,
框架更改通知的考虑范围
and if the height of that input
如果这个输入辅助视图的高度
accessory view changes, it will
有所改变 你就会收到
send a frame change
一个框架
notification.
更改通知
So, you can take care of that in
这样 你就可以在
the app that the keyboard is in.
这个键盘所在的 App 中处理它
Let's talk about making a
我们下面来聊一聊关于如何创造一个
dynamic height changing input
动态的高度可变的
accessory view, because this is
输入辅助视图 因为这是
something that a lot of people
很多人都想知道如何
want to be able to do.
去做的一件事
So, when you're doing this, this
当你这样做的时候
acts a lot like a self-sizing
这就会像一个可以自己调节大小的
table view in that you want to
表格视图 在其中你可以
take whatever view is going to
应付任何种类的
be changing size, and use it to
可能变换大小的视图 并用它来
define the height of the view.
定义视图的高度
And you can do this with more
你可以将这种方法用于
than one, but in this example,
多种视图 但在这个例子中
we'll use a UI text view to show
我们将用一个 UI 文本界面来展示
how this might be done.
要怎么做
If you pin -- you can pin it to
如果可以的话
the top and bottom of the
你可以把它固定在
content view with spacing if
内容界面的顶部或者底部
applicable.
并且留出一些空间
And if there are views in
如果中间还有其他界面的话
between it, that's fine as long
只要高度被定义好了
as the height is fully defined.
其实没有太大问题
Again, it's very similar to
它与可以自动调整大小的
self-sizing table view cells.
表格视图单元很相似
At that point, you need to use
此时 你需要使用
or define the intrinsic content
或是定义你的成长视图的
size of your growing view, so
intrinsicContentSize 这样
that the input accessory view
你的输入辅助视图才会知道
knows how talk it needs to be.
它需要什么高度
With a text view specifically,
在文本视图中
in order for it to have its own
为了使它有自己的
intrinsic content size so that
intrinsicContentSize 而使得
you don't have to define it, you
你不用再去定义
need to tell its text container
你就需要告诉它的文本容器
to have its height track the
让它的高度跟着
text view.
文本视图而变化
And you also need to disable
同时你还需要禁用
scrolling.
滚动
At that point, the text view
这样 文本视图就会依据
defines its internal --
视图中文本的多少而
intrinsic content size, based on
定义它自己的内在的
the amount of text in the view.
intrinsicContentSize
And you can get something like
你就会得到像这样
this.
的情况
So, this is one of the few cases
所以 这是你
where you may need to actually
可能实际上需要
override intrinsic content size
在输入辅助界面覆盖
in the input accessory view.
intrinsicContentSize 的几种情形之一
And to do that, you don't want
为了完成这样的效果
to spend, you know -- don't want
你恐怕不想
to make it too complicated.
把它弄的太过复杂
It's actually not too bad.
其实它并没有那么难
Grab the bounds as they come in.
当键盘可见时 抓取它的边界值
That's going to be your original
这将是你的原始
bounds, and we'll make sure that
边界 然后我们会确保
you have the correct width,
你的宽度值是正确的
which is already given to you by
而这个宽度值已经
the system.
由系统给出了
In my case, I always like to
对我来说 我一般习惯
make sure that the view has a
确保视图有一个
minimum height, so I set it to
最小高度 所以我先把它设置为
minimum height first, just in
一个最小高度值
case everything else -- all my
以防万一 一切其他
other ifs are elses.
可能出现的情况都是“万一”
And then, if my expanding view
然后 如果我的扩展视图的
is the correct height, I use
高度是正确的 我就用
that plus some vertical padding
这个高度加上
I've previously defined to
我之前定义的 kVerticalPadding
define the new height of the
来定义视图的
view.
新高度
I also have a maximum height
我同时会有一个最大高度
because there's only so much I
因为我每次
actually should type to my cats
实际上给我的猫说的话
at once.
就那么多
They don't have great attention
猫不会有很长的集中注意力
spans.
的时间
So, at a point, it stops.
所以 在某个时刻 我会停止
At that point, you simply return
在那个时候 你只需要返回
your new intrinsic content size,
你的新的 intrinsicContentSize
and your input accessory view
而你的输入辅助视图
will grow.
将会随之变化
Okay, so we have now talked
好的 那么我们已经讨论过了
about integrating the keyboard
如何将键盘整合到
into your layout, and adding a
你的布局中 以及如何添加
dynamic input accessory view.
一个动态的输入辅助视图
Now, we have an app where I can
现在 我们有了一个我可以用来
talk to my cats, and I can say
跟我的猫聊天的 App  并且我可以
more than a couple of words at
一次说好几句话
once, which is nice.
这很棒
He doesn't need very many words.
我的猫不需要很多很多词
He's very specific in what he
它对我的要求也
needs from me.
非常明确
But there's more cool things
但是有很多很酷的事情
that we can do with this app to
可以让我们把这个 App
make it a lot more interesting.
变得更有趣
So, I'm going to hand this over
现在让我把话筒
to Shuchen, and she's going to
给 Shuchen 她将会
tell you all about how to make
告诉你们如何
your app feel more magical.
使你们的 App 变的更赞
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hello, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
So, in iOS, we provide a lot of
在 iOS 中 我们提供了很多
sweet features so that you can
有趣的产品让你可以
improve our user text input
提升用户的文本
experience.
输入体验
My name is Shuchen Li.
我叫 Shuchen Li
I'm going to talk a few of them.
我将谈到它们其中的一些
So, I hope after my talk you can
我希望在这之后你们可以
utilize these tricks and make
运用它们 为你的 App 带来
your app feel magical.
更赞的使用体验
So, let's get started.
那我们就开始吧
So, first of all, let me ask a
首先 请允许我问
question.
一个问题
Who are multilingual people
在座的有谁会说
here?
多种语言
Oh, I see quite a few.
哦 我看到有一些
So, am I. Do you face the
我也是 你们是否遇到过
situation that you have to keep
这样的情形 就是需要
switch keyboard?
一直切换键盘
Oh, I see one there.
我看到这边有一个
Oh, I see a few of you there.
这边也有几个人
Good. I suffer that problem too.
很好 我也很头疼这个问题
And I have to talk to my boss
我跟我的上司交谈需要用
with one keyboard.
一种键盘
I talk to my mom with another
我跟我妈妈交流需要用
keyboard.
另外一种键盘
I have to keep switch between
我不得不一直在
these.
两者之间切换
What if your app just know what
如果你的 App 知道你应该用
keyboard you use?
哪个键盘会怎么样呢
What if when keyboard brings up,
如果当你的键盘出现时
it's just the right keyboard for
它就是你想要的
you?
那个键盘呢
Actually, you may know this.
实际上 你可能听说过
In our Message app, it does that
在我们的“信息” App 中
for you.
它就可以为你这样做
I talk to John with English
我跟 John 交流时
keyboard.
使用英文键盘
I talk to my [inaudible] with
我跟 Vivian 交流时用的是
Chinese keyboard.
中文键盘
And Magic knows what keyboard
而“信息”知道我要用的是
I'm using.
哪种键盘
How does that work?
这是如何做到的
In iOS, we can associate a
在 iOS 中 我们可以把
unique identifier called Text
一个特殊的标识符 叫做
Input Context Identifier, with
文本输入上下文标识符 和你的
your text view.
文本视图联系在一起
Actually, we can associate that
事实上 我们可以把它和
with all your UI Responder.
所有你的 UI 响应器联系起来
That is, you can also do that
也就是说你也可以对
with your view controllers.
你的视图控制器这样做
So, when we see you have a
这样 当我们看到你
unique identifier set up,
设定了一个标识符时
whether you're a responder, we
不管你是否是一个响应器
will associate that
我们都会把它
automatically with the user
自动跟用户选择的键盘联系起来
selected keyboard, and then save
然后把它保存为
that into user default.
用户默认设置
Next time, when you are a
下次 当你是一个
responder, becomes a first
响应器的时候 或成为首次
responder, the keyboard will be
响应器的时候 这个键盘将会被
retrieved automatically.
自动检索出来
Sounds complicated.
听起来很复杂
The only thing you need to worry
其实你所要担心的唯一的事情
about is to find a good unique
就是去找到一个好的
identifier.
唯一标识符
What are good unique
什么算是好的
identifiers?
唯一标识符呢
For example, your user ID, your
比方说 你的用户 ID
conversation ID, the group IDs,
对话 ID  群 ID
these are all good examples.
都是很好的例子
So, you may ask, "Where should I
那么 你或许会问 我把这些
put this unique identifier?
唯一标识符放哪呢
You mentioned, yes, I can define
正如你提到的 没错 我可以在
it in all the UI responder.
任何 UI 响应器中定义它
Do I define it everywhere?"
我能在任何地方定义它吗
Of course not.
答案是不
So, let's see how we put it.
那么 让我们看看我们要怎么放置它
Let's recall our CatChat app.
让我们回忆一下 CatChat App
When we bring out the keyboard,
当我们拉出键盘时
the text view becomes the first
文本视图成为了
responder.
第一个响应器
And then what's next, in the
然后在响应链中的下一环
responder chain, is our
就是我们的
conversation view controller.
对话视图控制器
And then, it's navigation
然后是导航
controller.
控制器
And then, in iOS, when we look
于是 在 iOS 中 当我们为你的
for the unique identifier for
响应器寻找唯一标识符时
your responder, we will search
我们会搜索
and look up the responder chain
响应链来寻找
to look for the first one.
其中的第一环
So, in our app, we handle all
在我们的这个 App 中 我们在
our conversation in our
对话视图控制器中控制
conversation view controller.
全部的对话
So, we put it there.
所以我们把标识符放在那里
In such way, you don't have to
这样 你就不必
find a way you pass down your
想办法把你的标识符
unique identifier to your
传给你的文本界面或其他
[inaudible] or other places that
你希望传到
it want to pass in.
的地方
So, you just put in where you
你只要把它放在
handle all your conversations.
你处理所有对话的地方
Let's see how we transfer all
我们来看看如何把这些
these into code.
翻译成代码
In our conversation view
在我们的对话视图控制器中
controller, we override the
我们把 Guider
[inaudible] for Text Input
重写成了
Context Identifier.
textInputContextIdentifier
You can see this method.
你可以看到这个方法
It's very simple.
非常简单
It's just return a unique
它就会返回一个
identifier.
唯一标识符
In our case, we return our
在我们的这个例子中 我们返回
recipient's ID.
收件人 ID
Now, Kasia is going to show you
现在 Kasia 会为你们展示
a demo to see how we give our
一个 Demo 来看看我们是如何让我们的
app a memory.
App 拥有记忆的
Kasia?
Kasia
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; You may not remember me.
&gt;&gt; 你们可能不记得我了
It's been a while since I've
离我上次见到你们已经
seen you all.
有一段时间了
But Kasia's still on keyboards.
但 Kasia 还是在搞键盘
Okay, so first -- here we have
好的 首先 这是我们的
our CatChat app that we've been
CatChat App 就是我们
looking at today.
今天看到的那个
And I've got a couple of pets
我有一些宠物
that speak different languages.
它们说不一样的语言
I have my Misiu here.
这是我的 Misiu
He speaks Polish.
它说波兰语
And actually, I learned as a
实际上我小时候听说
child that all cats speak
所有的猫说的
Polish.
都是波兰语
So, it's important to speak
所以 对它们说
Polish to all of them.
波兰语很重要
But, my default keyboard as an
但是 作为一个英语母语的人
English speaker is English.
我的默认键盘是英语
So, if I go ahead and change it
如果我直接把它换成
to Polish, and say "Hello,"
波兰语键盘然后说“你好”
let's see.
然后看看会发生什么
And see, you know, how he's
然后你看 它今天
doing today.
过得怎么样
This is me saying, "Hey, how are
这是我在说“嘿 今天过得
you doing?"
怎么样”
And he wants food.
它说要吃的
This is so surprising.
这很让我惊讶
Well, let's check in on
那么 我们来看看
Shuchen's dog, Jiwang.
Shuchen 的狗 Jiwang
And Jiwang would like to go out
Jiwang 想现在出去
for a walk, but I don't
遛弯 但我
currently have time.
现在没空
However, he speaks Chinese, so
然而 它说中文 所以
I'm going to switch keyboards
我要把键盘再次
again to the Chinese pinyin
更换成中文拼音
keyboard, and say, "I don't have
然后说“我现在
time right now.
没有时间
Please be patient."
请耐心等待“
And dogs are a little bit
狗狗的回复
friendlier sometimes with their
有时候会比猫
responses than cats.
友善一点
So, now, this is the first time
所以 现在 这是我第一次
I've used this to talk to both
使用这个 App 同时跟它们
of them.
两个交谈
So, if I go back into Misiu's
如果我回到与 Misiu 的
conversation, the Polish
对话 波兰语
keyboard is still there.
键盘还在
And if I go back here, I still
如果我回到这里 我还会
have the Chinese keyboard.
看到中文键盘
So, I don't have to keep
所以 我就不用一直
switching keyboards, depending
切换键盘 取决于
on the conversation I'm in.
我在进行的是什么对话
And all that needed to happen
要实现这一点
for that to happen, was to set
要做的事 就是
that text input context
设置 textInputContextIdentifier
identifier, as Shuchen showed
正如 Shuchen 说的
you, with the unique ID of each
把它联系到每个对话的
individual chat.
唯一 ID
If I change languages now, my
如果我现在切换语言
app doesn't need to know what
我的 App 无须知道我在用的
language I'm in.
是什么语言
It just needs to know that it's
它只需要知道这是
in a specific conversation and
哪一个对话
we will take care of setting the
而我们会为你设置好
proper keyboard for you.
正确的键盘
So.
就是这样
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Okay, back to Shuchen.
好的 有请 Shuchen
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Kasia.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Kasia
A quite neat feature, right?
相当实用的功能 对吧
It'll save quite a bit of wear
它会省却你
and tear on your [inaudible] I
不少的麻烦
believe.
我相信这一点
So, in this whole process, you
所以 在整个过程中
may notice, you don't really
你可能也注意到 你不需要
need to care what keyboard the
关心用户选择的
user selected.
是什么键盘
You don't need to know.
你不需要知道
The only thing you need to worry
你需要担心的唯一一件事就是
about is the unique identifier
你的唯一标识符
that was set up.
是否设置好了
Now you may ask, what if you
现在你也许要问 如果你
want to know what's the language
想要知道用户在用的是什么语言
the user used?
怎么办
What if you want to develop a
如果你想为一个特定的语言
specific feature for a certain
开发一个特别的
language?
功能呢
Now you may want to look up UI
现在你可能需要查看
text input mode.
UITextInputMode
In UI text input mode, you can
在 UITextInputMode 中 你可以
easily access the primary
轻松找到用户的
language for the user.
主要语言
In such way, you can for
这样 你就可以
example, develop your own spell
比如 开发你自己的语言的
checker for your own language or
拼写检查器 或者
you can develop other specific
你可以针对你希望 App
feature for the specific
能够支持的某种语言
language that you want that
开发其他特别的功能
probably [inaudible] support
或者我们以后
where -- we will support maybe
有可能会支持的
in future.
语言
Now, next, we've been working
下一步 我们已经为
really hard on how to accurately
准确快速输入文本而
and quickly input text.
做出了很多努力
We made it further through a
我们可以通过
context scroll predictions.
语境滚动预测而使其进一步
Also, we take user personalized
同时 我们把用户的个性化信息
information into account.
考虑进来
Back in iOS 4, we introduced
在 iOS 4 中 我们推出了
keyboard types.
不同种类的键盘
There's different keyboard types
有了不同种类的键盘
like email keyboards, URL
比如电子邮件键盘
keyboards.
和 URL 键盘
If you're typing an email
如果你在输入一个邮件
address, the @ and the .com keys
地址 就会有 @ 和 .com 按钮
are there for easy typing.
使输入更简便
Last year, we introduced UI text
去年 我们介绍了
content type.
UITextContentTypes
UI text content type, it's a tag
UITextContentTypes 是一个
that you can set to your text
你可以设置在你的
view.
文本界面中的标签
It will provide all the context
它会通过这些标签提供
predictions through the tags.
各种语境预测
Let's see an example.
我们来看一个例子
So, now, John wants to add his
现在  John 想把他的猫
cat, Penny, into our CatChat
Penny 加入我们的
app.
CatChat App
This is John Appleseed's cat.
这个是 John Appleseed 的猫
From the video, you can see
从视频中 你可以看到
actually John didn't even type
实际上 John 根本没有用
on any of the letter keys.
任何字母按钮打字
He was just typing on the Quick
他只在用 QuickType
Type bar.
栏打字
All the informations are input.
所有的信息都输入了
Now, John wants to type the
现在 John 想要给猫
address for the cat.
输入 地址
So, that's John Appleseed's cat.
这是 John Appleseed 的猫
So, it lives in -- must be
它就住在 它应该
living in an Apple store.
住在一个 Apple Store
Which one?
哪一个
The one is Los Gatos.
Los Gatos 那个
For someone if we don't know,
如果有人不知道的话
Los Gatos means "cat" in
Los Gatos 在西班牙语中
Spanish.
是“猫”的意思
So, we can see, John went to the
于是 我们可以看到 John 打开了
map and browsed the Apple store
地图 搜索 Apple Store
and see what's the address.
查看地址
And then come back to our
然后回到我们的
CatChat app.
CatChat App
And then you will see, ta-da,
然后你就看到 哈
the address are there,
地址神奇
magically.
地出现了
And by typing on the Quick Type
通过用 QuickType 栏
bar, you can -- thank you.
输入 你可以 谢谢
If I type on the Quick Type bar,
如果我用 Quick Type 栏输入
you can directly input the whole
就可以直接
address.
输入整个地址
If you look closely, you can see
如果你仔细看 你可以看到
its source.
它的来源
It's from Map, in our case.
在这个例子中 它来自于“地图”
So, in iOS, we've been pulling
在 iOS 中 我们会整体提取
all user information and user
所有的用户信息和
activities as a whole, to come
用户活动 并加上
with the data source, to improve
数据来源 来提高
user's experience.
用户体验
For example, our keyboard
比如说 我们的个性化键盘
personalization also can extract
可以提取姓名
names to form keyboard
来构建键盘
personalization lexicon.
的个性化词库
Also, one more thing I want to
另外 还有一件事
mention.
我想谈谈
In this whole process, your app
在这个整个过程中 你的 App
is not only a passive receiver.
并不只是一个被动的接收者
Your app can be a contributor.
你的 App 可以是一个贡献者
Your app can contribute your
你的 App 可以通过
app's activity through NS User
NSUserActivity API
Activity APIs.
共享 App 活动
So, for example, if your browse
比如 如果你在
your favorite restaurant in
Yelp 上浏览你喜欢的餐厅
Yelp, the address can be
地址就会被
displayed on the Quick Type bar,
显示在 QuickType 栏上
if you set the tag properly.
如果你正确设置了标签的话
So, sounds interested?
这是否激起了你的兴趣
If you want to learn more, don't
如果你想了解更多
forget to look at the session
不要忘记看去年的视频
from last year called "Increase
叫做“Increase
Usage of Your App Through
Usage of Your App Through
Proactive Suggestion."
Proactive Suggestion”
So, this year, we made it
今年 我们让它
further.
更进一步
We add some new tags for user
我们为用户名和密码
name and password.
增加了一些新的标签
When you label your log-in field
如果你正确标记了你的登录框的话
properly, we will automatically
我们会自动地
suggest user name and password
为你的 App 建议
for your app.
用户名和密码
And also, fill that for you.
当然 会帮你填好
The only thing you need to do,
唯一你所要做的是
if you set your tags properly,
如果你正确的设置了标签
this is a one line API super
这个 API 只有一行 非常简单
simple, and it will guarantee
它可以确保
that some of the Quick Type
一些 QuickType
suggestion will display.
建议能被显示出来
However, this is not the full
不过这并不是
story.
全部
If you want to make sure all
如果你想确保
your credentials displayed
你的信息在你的 App 中
properly with your app, because
正确显示
you may have a website to
因为你可能有一个网页
associate with your app, you'd
关联在你的 App 上
want to check out "Introducing
你可以查看“Introducing
Password Auto Fill for App"
Password Auto Fill for App”
session.
的视频
So, next up, we talk about some
下一步 我们要谈到一些
new smartness.
新的智能
This year, we introduced some
今年 我们为文本视图提出了
smartness into our text view.
一些新的智能
First one is Smart Quote.
首先是 SmartQuote
Here are typewriter quotes.
这些是打字机式的引号
They are straight and some
它们是直的
people don't like it.
一些人不喜欢
I don't like it.
我也不喜欢
These are typographic quotes.
这些是印刷式引号
I like it.
我很喜欢
They are curly.
它们是弯的
They're more legible.
更清晰
And actually, they're more
并且它们实际上
grammatically correct in the
在语法上更正确
language perspective.
从语言的角度来说
And this year, iOS will
今年 iOS 将
automatically convert your
自动地把你的
typewriter quote into
打字机式的引号变成
typographic quote.
印刷式引号
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
What's next?
下一步是什么
When you type on the middle bar
当你在打字打到一半时
line, sometimes you just think
有时候你在想
about, "Okay, a hyphen, an end
“好吧 一个连字符 一个短破折号
dash, and add dash," how to do
再来一个长破折号”
that.
这样要怎么做
From this year, we can input a
从今年开始 我们可以用一个破折号输入
hyphen with one dash.
一个连字符
We will automatically convert
我们会自动把
two dashes into an end dash.
两个破折号转换成一个短破折号
And then, add dash with three
然后三个破折号转换成
dashes of course.
一个长破折号
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Also, we introduce Smart
并且 我们提出了
Insertion and Smart Deletion.
Smart Insertion 和 Smart Deletion
If you work with tags before,
如果你之前使用过标签
you have to insert and delete a
你需要插入或者删除
paragraph or a phrase, you know
一个段落或者一个短语 你就会知道
what I'm talking about.
我在说什么
And not even mention the trouble
就更不必提
caused by punctuation.
标点符号带来的麻烦了
So, for example, in our example,
所以 举个例子 在我们的例子中
Vivian wants to bring Jiwang
Vivian 想带 Jiwang
also to the party, but then
去参加聚会 但当时
Jiwang was sick.
Jiwang 病了
So, we have to remove him.
所以我需要去掉它
Now, in this whole process, you
在这个过程中
have to deal with a space.
你不得不面对一个空格
That's the trouble.
这是个问题
Troublemaker.
是个麻烦
So, from today, we will take
从今天开始
care of all of that for you.
我们会替你解决这些
With Smart Insertion and
使用 Smart Insertion 和
Deletion, we'll take care of all
Deletion 我们会替你处理所有
the leading and trailing spaces
字前和字后
for you.
的空格
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Also, I want to mention, all the
同时 我想说 所有的这些
smartness that we introduced
我们提出的智能
that I have talked about today,
包括我今天说的
they are all by default.
都是默认设置的
But I want you note, for these
但我希望你们知道
smart text input traits, they
那些智能文本输入功能
have three values.
它们有三个值
They have yes, no, and the
它们有“yes” “no”
default value.
以及“default”
We set the default value for
我们为你们全部设置了
default for all of you.
默认值
We will automatically do the
我们会为你们自动
right thing for you.
做好正确的选择
For example, if you have a text
比如说 你有一个文本框
field, you set the Secured Text
你把 securedTextEntry
Entry to Yes.
设置成“是”
Probably it's the password
它可能是一个
field.
密码栏
In that case, if you set your
这种情况下 如果你把
smart traits to default, we will
智能功能设为默认 我们会
automatically disable the smart
自动禁用 SmartQuote
quote conversion for you,
转换器
because we think probably that's
因为我们认为那可能
the user password.
是用户密码
We don't want to switch user
我们不想更改用户
typing for a password field.
在密码栏里的输入
If you recall, actually we can
如果你回忆一下 实际上我们可以
config auto correction types.
配置自动更正
We can config auto
可以配置
capitalization types.
自动大写
There are a lot of sweet traits
我们在文本输入中
that we have in Text Input
有很多很好的功能
traits.
可以使用
All of them have this default
他们全部都有
value.
默认值
What I want to emphasize here
我在此想要强调的是
is, before you play with any of
在你使用任何
these traits, always understand
这些功能之前 你一定要明白
what your tags is going to be.
你的标签会是什么
Always understand what the tags
也要明白你期待
you're expecting the user to
用户会输入什么样的
type.
标签
So, let me ask another question.
现在让我再问一个问题
Who flew to San Jose for WWDC?
有谁为了 WWDC 飞到圣何塞的
Well, welcome.
好的 欢迎
So, am I. Kidding this time.
我也是 其实这次我是开玩笑的
If you have a text entry, only
如果你需要一个文本输入框
take flight code as an input, in
只采用航班号作为输入
such case, probably you want to
这种情况下 你可能需要
disable auto correction type and
禁用自动更正并且
auto capitalization type setting
把自动大写功能
to No.
设成“否”
Right? Because that makes sense.
是这样吧 因为这样才有意义
So, you always want to fully
所以 你必须要清楚的
understand your text before set
了解文本 再去设置
all these traits.
这些功能
Not just, okay, type on the tab
不是说就在这个标签上
and just say, "Okay, yes," or
打字 想“好的 就设成是”
"No," just by thing.
或者“否”
Always fully understand it.
你必须充分理解它
This is my point.
这是我的观点
Next, while work with text, you
下面 在处理文本时 你现在可以
can now ignore marked texts.
忽略标记文本
Two big names, Chinese and
两大语言
Japanese.
中文和日文
They all use marked texts.
都使用标记文本
So, marked text language call
标记文本语言
word, the marked text into final
把标记文本变成最终文本
text by select candidates.
是通过选字实现的
In iOS, actually you can easily
在 iOS 中 实际上你可以很方便的
access marked text from UI Text
在 UITextInput 中访问
Input.
标记文本
You can directly use the marked
你可以直接使用
We have an example in our system
我们的系统中就有一个这样的例子
is the Spotlight.
就是 Spotlight
In Spotlight, when user type in
在 Spotlight 中 当用户输入
Chinese for example, before
中文时 举个例子
users select the candidate,
在用户选字之前
Spotlight engine already start
Spotlight 引擎就已经开始
to show you all the results.
向你推荐搜索结果了
You can also do that in your app
你在你的 App 中也可以实现
through the marked text by
只需要通过将标记文本
retrieving it from UI Text
从 UITextInput 中提取出来即可
In such way, user won't be
这样 用户就不需要
interrupted by selecting
为选字而
candidate.
烦恼了
The user can spend more time to
用户可以有更多时间
enjoy your app.
来享受使用你的 App
I won't dive into too much about
我不会过多赘述关于
internationalization stuff, but
国际化的内容 但是
if you're interested, please
如果你感兴趣的话
watch Internationalization Best
请看去年的“Internationalization Best
Practices from last year.
Practices”视频
Last but not least, hardware
最后 硬件
keyboard.
键盘
I think everyone use hardware
我相信每个人都使用
keyboard and I believe you all
硬件键盘 我也相信你们都
love the keyboard shortcuts,
喜欢键盘快捷键
like Command C, Command V,
比如 Command C  Command V
probably your favorite is
你们最喜欢的可能是
Command Z.
Command Z
We brought that to iOS with
通过推出 Smart Keyboard
Smart Keyboard.
我们把快捷键带入了 iOS
So, in iOS, you can define your
这样 如果有 iPad App 的话
own shortcut for your user if I
你可以在 iOS 中
have iPad app.
为你的用户定制快捷键
So, let's see, how we do that.
那么我们来看一下 这是如何做到的
Let's dive right into the code.
我们就直接说代码吧
It's very straightforward and
非常直接
easy.
也非常简单
Again, in UI Responder, you can
同样的 在 UI 响应器中 你可以
override the key commands.
重写 KeyCommand
Key commands return an array of
KeyCommand 会返回一系列的
key commands.
关键命令
That means you can define a
这就意味着你可以
couple shortcuts for your app at
同时为你的 App 定制
the same time.
一些快捷键
To define a key command is very
定义一个 KeyCommand 是
straightforward.
清晰明了的
You give it inputs.
设定一个 input
You give a modifier.
设定你的 modifier
You put your selector there.
你把你的 selector 放在这里
And then also give it a name.
然后给它取一个名称
Also, don't forget to localize
不要忘了本地化
your name.
这个名称
This is our second shortcut.
这是我们的第二个快捷键
Now, press on the Command key,
现在 按下 Command 键
it will display the keyboard
它就会显示你的
shortcut for you and then you
键盘快捷键 然后
can see in our CatChat app, we
你就可以在我们的 CatChat App 中看到
have Command Up and Command Down
我们用 Command Up
to switch between the
和 Command Down
conversations.
来切换对话
So, let's recap.
现在我们回顾一下
I've talked about the
我们刚才讨论了
multilingual problem to how to
关于多语言的问题及如何
give your app a memory.
让你的 App 拥有记忆
I've talked about how to take
还有怎样
most advantages out of the
最大程度的利用语境来
context for predictions by
提高预测
giving your text field a tag
就是通过 Text Content Type
through text content type.
给你的文本框加个标签
I talked about the new smartness
我们还谈到了新的
for text input fields.
文本输入智能
I also talked about the mark
我们也提到了
text.
标记文本
Last but not least, there's
最后 还有一个
keyboard shortcuts you'll want
键盘快捷键功能 你们或许会
to try out.
感兴趣
Try them all.
多多尝试它们
Next, James is going to talk
现在 请 James 来谈谈
about how to create a custom
如何创建自定义
input views.
输入界面
James?
James
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Shuchen.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Shuchen
I'm very nervous -- I mean,
我很紧张 我的意思是
excited to tell you about
我很兴奋 能够跟你们讨论
creating custom input views.
创建自定义输入界面
So, Shuchen briefly mentioned a
Shuchen 已经简要提及了一个
UI Responder property called
UI 响应器的属性 叫做
Keyboard Type, which allows you
Keyboard Type 它允许你
to access a lot of the built-in
访问很多内置的
iOS system keyboards for
iOS键盘 并用于
specialized input, such as the
特殊的输入 比如说
decimal pad for entering decimal
用数字键盘输入数字
numbers, and we also have a
或者用
phone pad for entering phone
电话号码键盘输入电话号码
numbers, and a special keyboard
还有一个特殊的键盘
just for URLs and email
专门输入 URL 和址
addresses.
电子邮件地
Sometimes though, this may not
然而有时候 这可能还是
be enough for your application.
不能满足你的 App 的需要
You may want to go beyond what
你可能希望用到一些
the system keyboard provides
系统键盘还
you.
不能提供的功能
Let's take a look at a couple of
我们来看一些
examples.
例子
So, mathematics is a pretty good
数学是一个很好的
In math, there's a lot of custom
在数学中 有很多自定义的
symbols like Greek letters,
符号 比方说希腊字母
superscript operators, and
上标运算符
subscript operators.
或下标运算符
It could be pretty difficult to
要想使用系统内置键盘
type something like this with
来输入这些东西
the built-in system keyboard.
可以说是很难的
Swift Playgrounds is another
Swift Playgrounds 是另一个
good example.
很好的例子
This is the Swift Playgrounds
这是 Swift Playgrounds
app.
App
They have the standard QWERTY
它使用的是普通 QWERTY 界面
layout, but they provide a lot
但是他们同时提供很多
of additional functionality for
其他的功能
frequently used symbols in the
适应在 Swift 语言中常用的
Swift programming language.
一些符号
And they also have a really nice
他们还有一个很不错的
accessory bar in the top here,
在键盘上方辅助工具栏
for quickly inputting relevant
协助用户快速输入相关的
functions and symbols.
功能与符号
And then lastly, Apple numbers,
最后 Apple 的 Numbers
spreadsheets, is another good
电子表格是又一个
example.
很好的例子
So, there's a formula entry bar
这是一个公式输入栏
here, which also requires a lot
也需要有很多
of custom symbols, and they also
自定义符号 同时他们还有
have a nice, dark gray
一个深灰色的
background here, so it blends in
背景 因此它可以
really nicely with the system
很好地融入
keyboard.
系统键盘
So, going back to our CatChat
那么让我们回到 CatChat App
app, it's another pretty good
这是另一个
example for something that needs
需要自定义输入界面的
a custom input view.
很好的例子
Why? Well, right now, we have a
为什么呢 现在我们已经可以
way to talk to our pets, but our
跟我们的宠物聊天了 但是
pets don't have a way to talk
我们的宠物却不一定可以
back to us.
回复我们
And that's because, they have a
那是因为 它们
lot of trouble using the QWERTY
在使用 QWERTY 时有
keyboard.
很多困难
Their paws are quite large.
它们的爪子都比较大
The keys are really small.
而键盘的按键非常小
And so, they have a lot of
这样 它们很难
difficulty hitting those keys.
按到这些按键
Plus, they have a really limited
另外 它们的词汇量也
vocabulary too.
非常有限
So, they don't really need to
这样它们其实不需要
say a whole lot.
说很多话
So, let's say we want to make a
比方说现在我们要为
keyboard just for them,
这些宠物特制一个键盘
accessible to cats and dogs.
使小猫小狗都可以用
So, maybe we want just large
那么我们可能需要大号的
graphical buttons to represent
图形按钮来代表
their entire small vocabulary.
它们有限的词汇量
So, here's what that might look
它可能看起来
like.
是这样
This is our PetChat app, again.
这是我们的 Catchat App
It's the -- it's got the cool,
它已经拥有了
expanding text view that Kasia
Kasia 之前为我们创建的
built for us earlier.
酷炫文本界面
And now, on the pet side, we
现在 在宠物那一边
have three, large graphical
我们有三个大号的
buttons with -- representing
图形按钮 代表
their entire vocabulary of
它们的全部词汇
things they might want to say
包括它们想说的话
like, "I need food," "I want to
比如“我想要食物”
go outside," and "Stop petting
“我想出去”和
me."
“别摸我”
Something like that.
差不多就是这样
The other cool thing too is that
另一件很酷的事是
this behaves just like the
这个键盘使用起来就像
system keyboard does.
系统键盘一样
It sits at the bottom of the
它处在屏幕
screen.
的下方
There's an accessory bar at the
上方有一个辅助栏
top that's laid out, right at
就恰好在键盘上方
the top of the -- where the
不管这个键盘在哪
keyboard would go.
都在键盘上方
And then also the scroll view in
同样 背景的滚动界面
the background, automatically
自动地将
adapts its content insets to the
它的内容适应
size of your custom input view.
你的自定义输入界面的大小
So, let's go into a little bit
我们来进一步看看细节
more detail, about how to build
如何构建
something like this.
一个像这样的东西
So, for our PetChat app, to
对我们的 PetChat App 来说
create something like this, all
要构建一个这样的东西 我们所要做的
we need to do is subclass UI
全部事情就是
Input View Controller.
在 UIInputViewController 加入子菜单
And by doing that, we get a lot
这样 我们可以
of stuff for free, such as the
轻而易举地获得很多东西
blurry gray background that
比如能模仿系统键盘外观的
mimics the system keyboard's
半透明的灰色背景
But most importantly, we provide
但最重要的是 我们提供了
you a way to access the
一种方法 使你可以访问到
currently interactive text field
目前用户选择的
that the user has selected.
活跃的文本框
And we do this via a special
我们通过一种叫做
property, called Text Document
textDocumentProxy 的
Proxy.
特别属性
Now the Text Document Proxy
现在 textDocumentProxy
allows you to access things like
允许你访问
the text input traits for the
现在用户选择的文本框的
currently selected text field.
文本输入功能
So, that would be stuff like
这样 这就变成了
whether or not it's a password
判定这是否是一个密码栏
field, what kind of content type
什么样的内容形式更好
it prefers, and even what kind
甚至什么样的
of keyboard type it prefers.
键盘更适合的问题
So, you can adapt as necessary.
这样你就可以按照你的需求进行调整
But most importantly, the Text
但最重要的是
Document Proxy also allows you
textDocumentProxy 还允许你
to insert text into the text
在文本框中插入文本
field, via a simple method
通过一个非常简单的方法
called Insert Text, which just
叫做 InsertText 方法
takes a string.
只占用一个字符串而已
Oh, and one more thing that you
你还可以
can do with the Text Document
用 textDocumentProxy
Proxy too.
做一件事
You can access where the
你可以访问
insertion point position is, and
插入点的位置 以及
the text before and after the
它之前和
insertion point.
之后的文本
Pretty cool.
这非常棒
So, let's talk about how we can
我们来看看
actually get this inside of our
我们要怎样
PetChat app.
把它放入我们
Well, let's go back to our old
PetChat App 中让
friend here, the conversation
我们回到我们的老朋友
view controller.
ConversationViewController
So, to get it to show up in our
为了让它出现在我们的
conversation view controller, we
ConversationViewController 中
simply need to instantiate our
我们只需要把
custom input view as a member
customInputView 实例化成为
variable.
一个成员变量
And then, override a UI
然后 重写一个叫做
Responder method called Can
canBecomeFirstResponder	 的
Become First Responder, to
UI 响应器方法
return True, so that it becomes
使它返回 True 这样它就成了
a part of the responder chain.
响应链的一部分
And then lastly, all we need to
最后 我们所要做的
do, is override this other UI
只是重写另一个叫做 inputView 的
Responder method called Input
UI 响应器
View.
方法
And then just return our custom
然后只需要返回我们的自定义
input view instance.
输入界面样本
Now, if you're using things like
现在 如果你正在使用
UI Text View or UI Text Field,
UITextView 或 UITextField
you actually don't need to do
你实际上不需要做以上的
most of this.
大部分工作
UI Text View and UI Text Field,
UITextView 和 UITextField
the input view property is a
输入界面属性是一个
writable property.
可写的属性
So, all you really need to do is
所以 你所要做的只是
actually just assign your custom
把你的自定义
input view instance to the input
输入视图样本赋给
view property.
输入视图属性
So, now, our pets have a way of
现在 我们的宠物已经
talking back to us in the
有办法跟我们在
PetChat app, but let's say they
PetChat App 中聊天了 但是如果它们
actually do kind of want to
事实上真的想要
break out a little bit and start
更进一步 开始
Tweeting or maybe writing a
写推特或是
blog.
写个博客
I'm sure they have a lot of
我很确定它们一定有
interesting things to say with
很多有趣的事情要说
that small vocabulary of theirs.
就用它们这少得可怜的词汇量
So, in iOS 8, we actually added
所以在 iOS 8 中 我们添加了
the ability to create custom
创建自定义键盘扩展的能力
keyboard extensions, so that it
这样它可以
runs anywhere in the system.
在系统中的任何地方运行
This is actually our first time
事实上 这是我们第一次
talking about it at WWDC.
在 WWDC 讨论这个问题
So, here's what our custom
那么 我们的自定义
keyboard extension might look
键盘扩展可能会
like, running inside of
像这个样子在“信息”中
messages.
运行
So, you can -- your pets can
这样 你的宠物就可以
chat anywhere, or type into
在任何地方聊天 或者在
Twitter or keep a blog or
Twitter 上打字 或是写个博客
something.
什么的
So, it's actually really easy to
因此 实际上很容易
go from an input view into a
从一个输入视图到
custom keyboard extension.
自定义键盘扩展
And so, I'm going to give you a
我要给你们一个
quick demo and show you how to
Demo 来展示你们要具体
do that.
怎么做
So, let's switch over to the
我们来看到这个电脑
Okay, so this is our custom
这就是我们的自定义
input view controller here.
输入视图控制器
I'm not going to go into too
我不会说太多关于
much detail about how it was
它是如何构建起来的
built, but our sample code is
我们的示例代码已经
uploaded online.
上传到了网上
So, you can download all this
你可以下载全部代码
yourself if you want to take a
如果你想进一步
look at it.
了解的话
But to take -- let's go ahead
那么我们就开始
and build and run this first to
生成然后运行这些代码
see what it looks like inside of
来看看它在
our app.
我们的 App 中是什么样子
Build and run.
构建 运行
Alright, so here's our custom
好了 这就是我们的
input view running inside of our
自定义输入界面在我们的
app.
App 中运行的样子
And so, I'm going to pretend
这样 我要开始装作
like I'm a pet and just start
我是一只宠物 然后开始
saying what I'm feeling.
说我的感受
I didn't have breakfast this
我今天早上没吃早饭
morning, so I'll do something
所以我就说
like that.
这个
So, now, if we actually want to
现在 如果我们想要
take this custom input view and
使用这个自定义输入界面并且
convert it into a third-party
将它转换成一个第三方
keyboard extension, it's quite
键盘扩展
easy.
是很简单的
So, let's switch back over to
让我们切换到
Xcode here and I'll show you how
Xcode 我会向你们展示
to do that.
如何完成
So, first, I'm going to go over
首先 我需要先
here to the top left, to the
把鼠标挪到左上方
Project Settings.
点击“Project Settings”
And I'm going to create a new
然后我要创建一个新的
target by clicking this plus
目标 点击这个加号按钮
button at the bottom here.
在屏幕底部
And so, I'm going to go ahead
然后我就要继续操作
and choose the custom keyboard
选择自定义键盘
extension template, and click
扩展模版 然后点按
Next.
“Next”
And give it a name.
取个名称
I'll just call it Animal
我就叫它 Animal Keyboard
Keyboard.
好了
So, now, by doing this, Xcode
好了 这样做之后 Xcode 实际上
actually already gives us a
已经自动给了我们
bunch of stuff for free.
很多东西
For instance, it sets it up so
比如 它完成设置后
that this extension is
这个扩展已经
automatically embedded inside of
自动的嵌入到了
your app bundle.
你的 App 数据包里
So, you don't need to mess with
这样你就不需要纠结
build settings or build phases
构建设置或者构建阶段
or anything like that.
等一系列问题
And it also gives us a template,
它同时还给了我们一个模版
UI Input View Controller, here.
UIInputViewController
But we actually don't need to
但我们其实不需要
use this because we already
用到它 因为我们已经
wrote one.
写了一个
So, I'm just going to tweak
所以我只需要
around with a couple of settings
调整一些设置
here, so that our extension
保证我们的扩展
loads are already built, Custom
能正确装载
Input View Controller, instead
CustomInputViewController
of the one that the template
而不是
gives us.
模版给我们的那个
So, I'm going to go over here to
我要切换到
our Custom Input View
我们的 CustomInputViewController
Controller, and I'm going to
然后我要
check the box over here for our
勾选这里这个复选框框
keyboard extension so that it's
这样我们的键盘扩展就成为
a member of that target.
那个目标的一部分了
And then, our keyboard uses a
然后 我们的键盘用到了
couple of other resources.
一些其他资源
It has a couple of localized
它有一些
strings.
本地化的字符串
So, I'm also going to go ahead
所以我也要把这里
and switch to localized strings
切换到本地化字符串
and check this checkbox to make
然后勾选这个框
sure it's part of that target.
以确保它是那个目标的一部分
And then lastly, it also has a
最后 它还有一些
couple of assets that it uses
用于图像的
for images.
内容
So, I'm going to check this box.
所以我要勾选这个框
And then, one more thing I have
然后我还要做
to do.
一件事
I'm going to go over to the info
就是到 Info.plist 中
P-list here, that it generated
这是为
for our custom keyboard
我们的自定义键盘扩展而生成的
extension, and change its
然后把它的
principle class to the one that
主要类改成我们
we already made, from the one
之前创建的那个键盘 而不是
that the template gave us.
模版给出的那个
And that's pretty much it.
这样就差不多了
So, I'm going to switch back to
现在我要切换回到
the app target here and build
App目标 然后构建
and run.
并运行
So, now that the app is
好了 现在这个 App 已经
installed on the system, the
安装在系统里了
extension came along with it.
扩展也跟它一起安装好了
And there used to be -- now we
现在我们得
have to enable the custom
在系统设置里开启自定义
keyboard extension in the System
键盘扩展
Settings, and there used to be a
过去这是一个很
really convoluted way to do
复杂费解的
that.
过程
But in new, in iOS 11, we
但在新的 iOS 11 里
actually made it much simpler
我们为用户简化了
for your users to enable your
开启你的
custom keyboard extension.
自定义键盘扩展的方式
So, I'm going to show you how
那么我要向你们展示
that works right now.
它现在是如何工作的
So, I'm going to go back to
让我回到
Settings.
“设置”
So, all you need to do, to
现在你要开启
enable your -- to allow your
允许你的用户
users to enable your custom
来开启你的自定义键盘
keyboard, is provide your app
你所要做的就是给你的 App
with a Settings Bundle.
提供一个“设置”包
It can be empty or it can
它可以是空的 它也可以
contain some of your settings.
包含你的一些设置
And we have this new option,
我们现在有个新的选项
right underneath there, under
就在这里
Siri and search that just says,
在 Siri 和搜索下面叫做
"keyboards."
“键盘”
And by clicking this, the user
点击这里
-- all the user has to do is
用户要做的所有事情就只是
check this one switch.
滑动这个滑块
And now the keyboard's enabled.
现在键盘就被激活了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
I'm sure you third-party
我很确定你们这些第三方
keyboard developers are going to
键盘开发者会
love that.
爱上它的
So, now, I'm just going to go
现在 我切换到
over to messages here.
“信息”
And then, I'm going to switch to
然后我要切换到我们的
our custom keyboard extension.
自定义键盘扩展
And there we go.
好了
Now we have it running, all over
现在我们使它在整个系统中
the system.
运行了
And so, I'm just going to
现在我想
express how I'm feeling about
说说我现在对这个
the demo right now.
Demo 的感觉
And that's all it takes.
我要做的就是这样
So, let's go back over to the
让我们再回到
slides.
幻灯片
[ Applause ]
[鼓掌]
Thanks. So, this is actually my
谢谢 这是我个人
personally recommended way for
推荐的方式来
you to develop third-party
开发第三方
keyboards.
键盘
It's really easy to test it
也很容易先在
inside of your app first, just
你的 App 中测试
as a custom input view.
作为一个自定义输入界面
And then, as you saw, going from
然后 正如你所见
a custom input view to a custom
从一个自定义输入界面到一个
keyboard extension is really
自定义键盘扩展是很容易的
easy.
一件事
So, that's really the way to go.
这真的是一个很好的方法
So, just a quick recap of how to
我们来快速的回顾一下
convert from a custom input view
如何把一个自定义输入界面转换成
to a keyboard extension.
一个键盘扩展
We just made a new target and we
我们只需要创建一个新的目标
used the Custom Keyboard
然后我们使用了自定义键盘
Extension Template.
扩展模版
You can either fill in the
你可以选择使用系统提供的
provided UI Input View
UIInputViewController
Controller Subclass, or change
子类 或者修改
it so that it works with your
使它能够运行你
own.
自己的键盘
And then lastly, I showed you a
最后我展示了一个
cool, new user acceleration or a
酷炫的新的用户快捷键 或者说
cool new acceleration for your
一个酷炫的让你的用户
users to enable your keyboard
在你的设置包里
from within your Settings
快速激活你的键盘的方式
But that's not all.
但这并不是全部
We have a couple of new APIs in
我们在 iOS 11 中有很多新的 API
iOS 11 that I want to share with
我想跟你们分享
you tonight -- or today.
它们
So, you can now access the
现在你可以快速访问
currently selected text that the
现在用户所选择的
user has selected, which is
文本 这十分有用
pretty useful if you want to do
如果你想要你的
retro correction with your Auto
自动完成引擎进行
Complete Engine, for instance.
反校正
Or provide some kind of cool
或者在用户选择的
context around the text that the
文本周边提供一些
user had selected.
很酷的背景的话
We also provide you this new
我们也提供了这个
thing called the Document
叫做 documentIdentifier
Identifier Handle, which is just
句柄的新功能
a UUID, that uniquely identifies
它是一个 UUID 能够准确地把
one text field from the next.
一个文本栏和下一个区分开来
Now, this is real useful for a
现在 这对很多事情
lot of things, but one of the
都非常有帮助
things that it's useful for is
其中一个就是
for resetting your keyboard
重置你的键盘的状态
state when the user switches
当用户切换
text fields, so you can clear
文本框时 这样你就能够
your predictions if you have
清空你的预测 如果你
predictions displayed, or switch
让预测显示出来的话 或者
back to the alphabetic plane if
切换回字母键盘
the user had switched to your
如果用户之前切换到了
numeric plane, or something like
数字键盘的话
that.
诸如此类
And lastly, we also added the
最后 我们还增加了一项功能
ability for you to query whether
让你可以询问用户
or not the user has granted your
是否同意了
extension full access.
你的扩展完全访问权限
And I'll go over what full
等一下我会谈到
access means in just a moment,
完全访问权限是什么意思
in case you're not familiar.
以防你们有人不熟悉
But first, I want to talk about
但是首先 我想谈谈
some other lesser known,
一些其他的 鲜为人知的
third-party keyboard APIs that
第三方键盘 API
maybe you didn't know about.
你们可能也不知道
So, in iOS 10, we actually added
在 iOS 10 中
the ability for you to
你们可以在键盘中
incorporate the System Globe
嵌入 System Globe
Menu inside of your keyboard,
Menu
which is really nice so that
这很方便 可以允许
your user can quickly switch
你的用户快速地
between all of the keyboards
在他们所选择的所有键盘中
that they have selected.
自由切换
It's a lot better than that next
这比起我们之前只能选
keyboard thing that we had
下一个键盘
before.
强多了
Oh, thanks.
谢谢
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
You can also personalize your
你也可以个性化你的
auto complete results with
自动补全结果
something that we call the
使用我们称为
Supplementary Lexicon.
Supplementary Lexicon 的功能
The Supplementary Lexicon is
Supplementary Lexicon 本质上就是
basically just a list of words
一串单词
containing the portion of the
包含了一部分的
user's address book, so you can
用户的通讯录 允许你
auto complete various names and
自动补全姓名和其他一些
stuff, that the user might be
用户在他们
referencing in the text that
正在输入的文本中想
they type.
参考的内容
And finally, tying back to some
最后 跟一些
of the multilingual support that
我们在 iOS 11 中添加的多语言支持
we added in iOS 11, that Shuchen
联系起来 就是 Shuchen 刚刚
was talking about earlier, your
谈到的那些
keyboard can use those document
你的键盘可以结合我谈到的那些文档标识符
identifier handle things that I
句柄的功能
was mentioning before, as a
作为一个多语言
multilingual hint.
的提示
So, if your keyboard supports
这样 如果你的
multiple languages, you too can
键盘支持 多种语言
behave like the system keyboard
你也能够
does, and change when
使它像系统键盘一样
appropriate.
再需要的时候切换
So, lastly, we can't talk about
最后 我们要谈
third-party keyboard extensions
第三方键盘扩展
without talking about privacy
就必须要谈隐私和
and user trust.
用户信任
So, privacy is very much a
保护隐私是
standard iOS feature that users
iOS 用户通常会
expect.
期待的标准特点
And users are made aware that
他们也清楚
all of their keystrokes are
他们每一次的按键都是
handled by your extension.
通过你的扩展实现的
So, if you're doing something
所以 如果你要对
with those keystrokes, such as
这些按键做什么的话 比如说
sending them offsite or
对它们进行备份 或者
analyzing them in some way, you
分析它们的话
should make sure to inform the
你应该确保你通知到了
user about this, and anonymize
用户 然后对
the data that's coming in, if
收到的数据进行匿名处理
you are sending it offsite.
如果你要备份的话
And lastly, most applications
最后 尽管大部分的 App
shouldn't actually need it, but
都不需要 但你
you can ask the user to provide
可以询问用户是否
your extension with full access,
给予你的扩展完全访问权限
which means access to some lower
包括访问系统中一些
level parts of the system.
较低层的部分
Let's talk a little bit about
我们来谈谈到底
what full access really means.
完全访问权限是什么意思
So, first of all, there's
首先
actually quite a bit of value in
事实上不要求完全访问权限
not asking for full access.
是有意义的
This is why we built the full
这就是我们最初创建了
access switch to begin with.
这个完全访问权限滑块的原因
It's not a speed bump for you
对你们来说 这并不是一个障碍
Instead, our Apple customers are
相反 Apple 的用户都是
very privacy conscious.
非常注重隐私的
Plus, your keyboards already
另外 你们的键盘已经
provide a lot of awesome
提供了很多很棒的
functionality right out of the
功能 一打开就可以用到
box, without full access.
即使没有完全访问权限
So, granting this should really
所以 允许完全访问权限应当只是
only supplement your existing
对于你现在的功能
feature set.
的一个补充
So, some examples of things that
你可能需要用到
you might need full access for,
完全访问权限的一个例子
is communicating with your main
是与你的主要 App
app.
沟通
So, if you need to build a
如果你需要在
bridge from your main app bundle
你的主要 App 和
to your custom keyboard
你的自定义键盘扩展之间构建一个桥梁
extension, if you want to access
如果你想访问
like a database or something
一个数据库或者
that you have stored there,
你之前存储的内容的话
you'll need to request for full
你需要为此请求
access for that.
完全访问权限
If you want to access a -- if
如果你想访问
you want to provide your user
如果你想为你的用户
with a repository of gif images
提供一个 GIF 图库
for instance, then you'll need
举个例子 那么你
to ask for full access to grant
需要请求完全访问权限
access to the networking stack
来获得在 iOS 上访问网络堆栈
on iOS.
的权限
So, for current location, in
对于当前位置
case you want to enrich your
如果你想要丰富你的
auto complete results with
自动补全功能
references to locations that the
通过提供用户在正在输入的文本中
user might be referencing to in
所可能用到的位置的话
the text that they type, you'll
你需要为获得当前位置
need to request for full access
请求完全访问
for the current location.
权限
And you'll also have to have the
并且你还需要让
user grant your main app access
用户允许你的主要 App
to your current location too.
访问当前位置
So, keep that in mind.
因此 请牢记这一点
And for the address book, most
对于通讯录
applications don't actually need
大部分的 App 其实并不需要用到它
this because of what I said
因为我刚才说过的
about the supplementary lexicon.
Supplementary Lexicon 功能
So, you actually don't need full
所以你并不需要
access to get to the address
完全访问权限
book.
来获得通讯录
But, if you want to access some
但是 如果你想要访问
more of the address book, like
通讯录的更多信息
the notes fields, or nickname,
比如备注部分 或者昵称
or something like that.
等等
Then you will need full access
那么你就需要完全访问权限
for that.
来取得了
And lastly, make sure that your
最后 确保你的
keyboard works without
键盘在没有完全访问权限的情况下
requesting for full access.
也可以工作
Like I said, there's a lot of
正如我说的
value in not asking for full
不请求完全访问权限也是很有意义的
access, and plus, your app will
另外 如果你的 App
actually get rejected if it
不能做到这点 它可能不会被
doesn't.
允许上架
Take a look at the App Store
如果想了解更多信息 请看 App Store
Guidelines for more information
Guidelines 关于此问题的规定
So, just a quick summary before
那么在我今天 不对 今晚告别你们之前
I leave you tonight, or today,
我们进行一个快速的回顾
sorry.
抱歉
I did that again.
我又说错了
Kasia showed you how to design
Kasia 向你们展示了如何
your app with the keyboard in
在考虑到键盘的情况下
mind and about keyboard
设计你的 App 以及键盘
avoidance.
需要避免的问题
Actually, we don't say
事实上我们不会说
"avoidance."
“避免”
We say, "embrace the keyboard."
我们会说“拥抱你的键盘”
Don't avoid it.
别试图避免
And Shuchen mentioned some
Shuchen 提到了很多
advanced traits to enhance the
先进的功能来提高
user's experience with some of
用户体验 用一些
the built-in system keyboards
内置的系统键盘
that you can pick from.
你们可以从中选择
And if that wasn't enough, we
如果那还是不够
showed you how to build custom
我们展示了如何创建
keyboard extensions and custom
自定义键盘扩展和
input views, and how going from
自定义输入界面
a custom input view to a
以及如果将一个自定义输入界面转化成
keyboard extension, is actually
键盘扩展 这实际上
quite a lot easier than you
比你们想象的要
think.
简单很多
So, make sure to like, comment,
最后 记得要点赞 评论
and subscribe, or check out our
和订阅 或者查看
sample page or sample app, here
我们的示例页面或 App
at WWDC 17, Session 242.
WWDC 17 第 242 节
All the code that you saw today,
今天你们所看到的所有代码
is right there.
都在那里
So, all the sample code that you
你们今天所看到的所有示例代码
So, go check it out.
记得去查看
Here's some related sessions.
有一些相关的会议视频
The Password Autofill for Apps
“The Password Autofill for Apps”
is definitely a good one to
绝对是值得
check out.
看看的
Mysteries of Auto Layout is
“Mysteries of Auto Layout”
great too for keyboard avoidance
对避免键盘
and -- or keyboard embracing.
或者应该说拥抱键盘 也是很有用的
Thank you.
谢谢